

PROFILE

Coming from a background in operations, Karl has since 2010, experience with the architecture, development and implementation of cloud and on-premise infrastructure in AWS and Microsoft Azure. He is a AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate as well as AWS Certified Developer and has working experience with Linux and Windows Servers, and has over the last two years, been functioning as the 3rd level technical support for some of Norway's largest insurance companies.

Automation, CI/CD and infrastructure as code are important principles that Karl adheres to in order to create a uniform and reproducible infrastructure quickly and easily. He works with tools such as Git, Terraform, Bash and

Python in addition to traditional programming languages such as Java, C#/.net, PHP and (No)SQL.

Karl lives on the bleeding edge of technology and is always keeping himself updated on new technology and makes it a big point to share knowledge with both collogues and other interested people.

KARL MATHIAS MOBERG

Cloud Consultant, SRE and Developer

EXPERIENCE

CLOUD CONSULTANT & SRE 2019 -

TietoEVRY - BERGEN

Cloud & Infrastructure consultant, specialized in AWS and DevOps. Key Projects include Lead Architect role on Government Big-Data AWS project, Architect and engineer on multiple cloud migration projects to AWS and Lead Architect on cloud native projects in Azure.

ORGANIZER / SPEAKER 2019 -

CLOUD NATIVE BERGEN - BERGEN

Help organize cloud native monthly meetups, functioning as an organizer and speaker.

IT SYSTEM-ADMINISTRATOR 2018 - 2019

MARKANT NORGE AS - BERGEN

IT Administrator for a company of 30 people, responsible for day-to-day IT services, in addition to managing large Magento online-stores in AWS.

NOC-ENGINEER/ KUNDEANSVARLIG 2012 - 2017

TELENOR NORGE AS - STAVANGER

Worked both as a NOC-engineer, responsible for all incoming mobilenetwork tickets for Business customers. Projects include an efficiency project that lowered average ticket queue time from 5 days to less than 6 hours.

EDUCATION

NETWORK -AND IT SECURITY 2018 - 2020

NOROFF - ONLINE

Courses includes Programming, SQL Databases, Preventative Security, Security and the Law and Entrylevel Digital Forensics.

NETWORK AND SYSTEMADMINISTRATION 2017 - 2018

NOROFF - STAVANGER

Courses includes Introduction to Information Security, Windowsand Linux Server, Networking and Operating- and File-systems.

CERTIFICATIONS

AMAZON WEB SERVICES 2020 -

Certified Developer Associate

AMAZON WEB SERVICES 2019 - **Certified Solutions Architect Associate**

CISCO 2015 - 2018

Cisco Certified Entry Network Technician

9

5089 Bergen, Norway



karlmathias@gmail.com



+47 40 55 11 09



www.kmoberg.no



linkedin.com/in/kmoberg

PRO SKILLS

PHP/SQL

JAVA

PYTHON

MONGODB

REACT

JAVASCRIPT

PHOTOSHOP

HTML

OPR SKILLS

AWS

AZURE

GCP

LINUX

WINDOWS

NETWORK